Here‘s a simple challenge: name a famous inventor.
有一个简单的挑战：说出一位著名的发明家。
Perhaps Renaissance polymath Leonardo da Vinci springs to mind.
也许文艺复兴时期的博学者列奥纳多·达·芬奇会马上浮现在脑海中。
Or the pioneer of the telephone, Alexander Graham Bell.
或者电话的先驱亚历山大·格雷厄姆·贝尔。
But you might be hard-pressed to name many female inventors, even though women are behind some of the most widely used technologies in the modern world.
但你可能很难说出许多女性发明家的名字，尽管现代世界一些应用最广泛的技术是由女性发明的。
For example, where would we be without the windscreen wiper?
例如，如果没有汽车挡风玻璃雨刷，我们会怎样呢？
Back on a freezing winter’s day in 1902, Mary Anderson was travelling by tram through New York city.
回到1902年一个寒冷的冬日，玛丽·安德森正乘坐有轨电车穿过纽约市。
Snow was falling, forcing the driver to stop repeatedly and get out to clear it.
当时正在下雪，迫使司机不断停车并下车清理积雪。
Each time the door opened, Mary suffered a gust of sub-zero air.
每次车门打开，玛丽都会遭受一阵零下的寒风。
She had a brainwave: why not make some kind of a rubber blade that could be operated from inside the vehicle?
她突然有了一个灵感：为什么不制作一种可以在车内操作的橡胶刮片呢？
And that‘s exactly what she did.
而她正是这么做的。
Let’s step in from freezing New York for our next invention.
让我们从寒冷的纽约转到下一项发明。
The dishwasher dates back even earlier to the 19th Century, and to the dinner parties thrown by a lady called Josephine Cochrane.
洗碗机的历史甚至可以追溯到更早的19世纪，这要归功于一位名叫约瑟芬·科克伦女士举办的晚宴。
As a frequent host, she wanted a machine that could wash dishes faster than people.
作为一个经常举办宴会的主人，她想要一台能比人更快洗碗的机器。
Her response was to develop what was to become the first commercially successful dishwasher.
于是她研制出了后来成为第一款商业上成功的洗碗机。
Interestingly, innovation was in her blood: her grandfather had invented the steamboat.
有趣的是，创新是她与生俱来的：她的祖父发明了汽船。
Need something to do while the dishwasher is whirling away?
当洗碗机嗡嗡作响时，需要找点事做吗？
How about a round of Monopoly?
来一局《大富翁》怎么样？
One of the most popular board games around, the rules were first drawn up by a lady called Elizabeth Magie, and patented in 1904.
作为最受欢迎的棋盘游戏之一，其规则最初是由一位名叫伊丽莎白·马吉的女士制定的，并于1904年获得了专利。
Her intention was to create a game to highlight what she saw as the evils of capitalism.
她的本意是创造一个游戏，以强调她所认为的资本主义的弊端。
The game was originally called The Landlord‘s Game.
这个游戏最初叫做《地主游戏》。
To an altogether different kind of innovation: Kevlar is the lightweight fibre used in bulletproof vests.
再来说说另一种完全不同的创新：凯夫拉是用于防弹背心的轻质纤维。
The material is used by millions every day and has saved countless lives.
这种材料每天被数百万人使用，并拯救了无数生命。
The super tough fabric is also used in objects ranging from gloves to aeroplanes to wind turbines.
这种超强韧的织物还被用于从手套到飞机再到风力涡轮机等各种物品。
Incredibly, its strength-to-weight ratio is five times higher than steel.
令人难以置信的是，它的强度重量比是钢的五倍。
Again, it was invented by a woman, the American chemist Stephanie Kwolek, in 1964.
同样，它是由一位女性，美国化学家斯蒂芬妮·克沃莱克在1964年发明的。
Finally, one of the most important inventions of the 20th Century must surely be the computer programme.
最后，20世纪最重要的发明之一肯定是计算机程序。
The world of programming is notoriously unbalanced in terms of gender.
众所周知，编程领域在性别方面存在着严重的不平衡。
Men vastly outnumber women, and take home around 30% more pay than their female counterparts on average.
男性的数量远远超过女性，而且平均而言，男性的收入比女性同行高出约30%。
But back in the 1940s and 50s, women were at the forefront of this new field.
但在20世纪40年代和50年代，女性处于这个新领域的前沿。
Grace Hopper is credited with inventing the first compiler in 1952, which serves as the bridge between code and the binary ones and zeros understood by computers.
格蕾丝·霍珀因在1952年发明了第一个编译器而受到赞誉，这个编译器是代码与计算机所能理解的二进制数字0和1之间的桥梁。